<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../resources/catalog.xsl'?>
<c:catalog xmlns:c="http://0install.de/schema/injector/catalog" xmlns="http://zero-install.sourceforge.net/2004/injector/interface"><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0compile.xml"><name>0compile</name><summary>create a binary release from source code</summary><description>
0compile creates a binary from source code, either for your own use or ready for
publishing on the web through Zero Install. It can use Zero Install to download
any build dependencies (compilers, header files, build tools, etc).

This is useful if there is no binary for your platform, or if you wish to modify
the program in some way.

If plash is installed, it is used to sandbox the build so that it can't
accidentally modifiy any files outside of the build directory.

For a full tutorial, see 0compile's homepage.</description><homepage>https://docs.0install.net/tools/0compile/</homepage><category>Development</category><needs-terminal/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0install-runenv-cli.xml"><name>0install-runenv-cli</name><summary>0install .NET helper for Windows</summary><description>
    When 0install needs to add a new program to %PATH% on Windows, it uses this
    package to creates a .NET launcher application.
</description><homepage>https://0install.net/</homepage><category>System</category></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0publish.xml"><name>0publish</name><summary>utility to make creating injector interfaces easier</summary><description>
0publish makes creating and modifying injector interface files easier. It can
create a new commented template for you or edit an existing one.

Various editing operations are available, the most basic being to let you edit
it in your preferred text editor. It automatically removes the signature when
loading an interface and creates a new one when writing it back out. It will
also validate the new version before saving it.

A tutorial on 0publish can be found at https://docs.0install.net/packaging/.</description><homepage>https://docs.0install.net/tools/0publish/</homepage><needs-terminal/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0publish-gui.xml"><name>0publish-gui</name><summary>GTK editor for Zero Install feeds</summary><description>
Publishing a program using Zero Install requires you to create an XML file
listing the available versions, where to get them, and what other software they
depend on.

This program provides a simple graphical interface for creating and editing
these feeds.</description><homepage>https://docs.0install.net/packaging/</homepage><icon href="https://0install.net/feed_icons/0publish-gui.png" type="image/png"/><category>Development</category></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0release.xml"><name>0release</name><summary>manage new releases with Zero Install</summary><description>
If you have a local feed in the development version of your program, 0release
can help you to create new releases easily.</description><homepage>https://docs.0install.net/tools/0release/</homepage><category>Development</category><needs-terminal/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0repo.xml"><name>0repo</name><summary>manage a repository of 0install feeds</summary><description>
    0repo allows a group of developers to publish a set of feeds. It can be
    used by a single developer, generating a set of static files to publish on
    a web-server, or as a service which accepts signed updates from a group
    of developers.
  </description><homepage>https://docs.0install.net/tools/0repo/</homepage><needs-terminal/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0template.xml"><name>0template</name><summary>utility to make creating feeds easier</summary><description>
    0template takes a template XML file (e.g. with place-holders for the version),
    fills in the place-holders, and then fills in everything else it can. For example,
    it will download the archive, fill in the size, calculate the digests, etc.
  </description><homepage>https://docs.0install.net/tools/0template/</homepage><needs-terminal/><entry-point binary-name="0template" command="run"/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0test.xml"><name>0test</name><summary>test Zero Install programs</summary><description>
Use 0test to run the unit tests for a Zero Install program. You can use this to
test released versions or developer snapshots. You can give a selection of
versions to test, and you can test against different versions of dependencies to
create a matrix of test results.</description><homepage>https://docs.0install.net/tools/0test/</homepage><category>Development</category><needs-terminal/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0watch.xml"><name>0watch</name><summary>scans websites for new releases and triggers 0template if required</summary><description>
    0watch scans websites for new releases using arbritary Python code snippets.
    When new releases are detected 0template is used to create/update a Zero Install feed.
  </description><homepage>https://github.com/0install/0watch</homepage><needs-terminal/><entry-point binary-name="0watch" command="run"/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/feedlint.xml"><name>FeedLint</name><summary>check your Zero Install feeds</summary><description>
FeedLint is a tool for Zero Install feed authors. It checks that your Zero
Install feed can be downloaded, that it is valid and that all the links in it
still work.

Run this on all your feeds from time-to-time to make sure they still work.</description><homepage>https://docs.0install.net/tools/feedlint/</homepage><category>Development</category><needs-terminal/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0install.xml"><name>Zero Install</name><summary>0install, the decentralized installation system</summary><description>Zero Install is a cross-platform, decentralized installation system. Instead of having a central repository in which all software is placed under a naming scheme managed by some central authority, programs and libraries in Zero Install are identified by URIs. Anyone who can create a web-page can publish software. Anyone can install software (not just administrators).</description><homepage>https://0install.net/</homepage><needs-terminal/><icon href="https://0install.net/feed_icons/ZeroInstall.png" type="image/png"/><category>System</category><entry-point binary-name="0install" command="run"/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0install-dotnet.xml"><name>Zero Install - .NET Core version</name><summary>.NET Core version of 0install, the decentralized installation system</summary><description>This is the .NET Core version of Zero Install. Zero Install is a cross-platform, decentralized installation system. Instead of having a central repository in which all software is placed under a naming scheme managed by some central authority, programs and libraries in Zero Install are identified by URIs. Anyone who can create a web-page can publish software. Anyone can install software (not just administrators).</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/0install-dotnet/master/icon.png" type="image/png"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/0install-dotnet/master/icon.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><homepage>https://github.com/0install/0install-dotnet</homepage><needs-terminal/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0install-ocaml.xml"><name>Zero Install - OCaml version</name><summary>OCaml version of 0install, the decentralized installation system</summary><description>This is the OCaml version of Zero Install. Zero Install is a cross-platform, decentralized installation system. Instead of having a central repository in which all software is placed under a naming scheme managed by some central authority, programs and libraries in Zero Install are identified by URIs. Anyone who can create a web-page can publish software. Anyone can install software (not just administrators).</description><homepage>https://0install.net/</homepage><icon href="https://0install.net/feed_icons/ZeroInstall.png" type="image/png"/><category>System</category></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0install-python.xml"><name>Zero Install - Python version</name><summary>Python version of 0install, the decentralized installation system</summary><description>This is the Python version of Zero Install. Zero Install is a cross-platform, decentralized installation system. Instead of having a central repository in which all software is placed under a naming scheme managed by some central authority, programs and libraries in Zero Install are identified by URIs. Anyone who can create a web-page can publish software. Anyone can install software (not just administrators).</description><homepage>https://0install.net/</homepage><icon href="https://0install.net/feed_icons/ZeroInstall.png" type="image/png"/><category>System</category></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0publish-win.xml"><name>Zero Install Publishing Tools</name><summary xml:lang="en">helps you create and update Zero Install feeds</summary><summary xml:lang="de">hilft Ihnen beim Erstellen und Aktualisieren von Zero Install Feeds</summary><description xml:lang="en">Zero Install uses feeds, XML files on the internet, to describe applications and how to download them. The Zero Install Publishing Tools allow you to create your own feeds. It consists of two main components:
the Feed Editor (split with screen graphical and XML view)
and the New Feed Wizard (walks you through the entire feed creation process, automatically extracts metadata when possible)</description><description xml:lang="de">Zero Install verwendet Feeds, XML Dateien im Internet, um Anwendungen sowie deren Download zu beschreiben. Die Zero Install Publishing Tools ermöglichen es Ihnen, Ihre eigenen Feeds zu erstellen. Sie bestehen aus zwei Hauptkomponenten:
Der Feed Editor (Split Screen mit grafischer und XML Ansicht)
und der New Feed Wizard (leitet Sie durch den kompletten Feed-Erstellungsprozess, extrahiert automatisch Metadaten wenn möglich)</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/0publish-win/master/icon.png" type="image/png"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/0publish-win/master/icon.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><homepage>https://docs.0install.net/tools/0publish-win/</homepage><entry-point app-id="ZeroInstall.Publishing" binary-name="0publish-win" command="run">
    <name xml:lang="en">Zero Install Publishing Tools</name>
  </entry-point><entry-point command="0publish">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">Feed Editor command-line</name>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/0install/0install-win.xml"><name>Zero Install for Windows</name><summary>Windows version of 0install, the decentralized installation system</summary><description>This is the Windows version of Zero Install. Zero Install is a cross-platform, decentralized installation system. Instead of having a central repository in which all software is placed under a naming scheme managed by some central authority, programs and libraries in Zero Install are identified by URIs. Anyone who can create a web-page can publish software. Anyone can install software (not just administrators).</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/0install-win/master/icon.png" type="image/png"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/0install-win/master/icon.png" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><homepage>https://0install.net/</homepage><entry-point binary-name="0install" command="run">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">Zero Install Command command-line interface</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">command-line interface for Zero Install, for installing and launching applications, managing caches, etc.</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="0install-win" command="run-gui">
    <name xml:lang="en">Zero Install Command GUI</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">WinForms-based GUI for Zero Install, for installing and launching applications, managing caches, etc.</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point app-id="ZeroInstall" binary-name="ZeroInstall" command="central">
    <name xml:lang="en">Zero Install Central</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">the main graphical user interface</summary>
  </entry-point></interface></c:catalog>
<!-- Base64 Signature
iQEzBAABCgAdFiEEiMih83WShpHXNlwCWao5J8JOTh4FAmBSFscACgkQWao5J8JOTh7IMQf+LQDF
E0QwgHMCR9ZPNlccMqWzUsCjhocFBs5+57f2gtYI2nQMbvpjtMaDHrq1zQ/droAAZOK2+W3xGe4i
23Ea5OEyEjlfe2Yq/LYtlECTvDH23t8mHeAzTj/0id5ML2j168twNAu/nlJYaqwArkQ2n3LvW580
sGJnLTnSYWGAqwnJ6dq1gtcRHFSH62BexLGshWDTCyPhpeau7lkScRSpDMv0pl0boULF/qoxV1NV
gs/U1EpTR172hkqsqgSQar6GRkKpA1FD7sF/1E54vQTDiJKZdHHTPtoTHKat+BmoYhpCGTtN3KIK
s9KM3Gu8tSO51A1gRf0u0TL17VlahTz9ZQ==

-->
