<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../resources/catalog.xsl'?>
<c:catalog xmlns="http://zero-install.sourceforge.net/2004/injector/interface" xmlns:c="http://0install.de/schema/injector/catalog"><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/glut.xml"><name>FreeGLUT</name><summary xml:lang="en">FreeGLUT is a free-software/open-source alternative to the OpenGL Utility Toolkit (GLUT) library.</summary><description xml:lang="en">GLUT was originally written by Mark Kilgard to support the sample programs in the second edition OpenGL 'RedBook'. Since then, GLUT has been used in a wide variety of practical applications because it is simple, widely available and highly portable.

GLUT (and hence FreeGLUT) takes care of all the system-specific chores required for creating windows, initializing OpenGL contexts, and handling input events, to allow for trully portable OpenGL programs.</description><category>Graphics</category><homepage>http://freeglut.sourceforge.net/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/glib.xml"><name>GLib</name><summary>low-level system libraries written in C</summary><description>GLib provides the core application building blocks for libraries and applications written in C. It provides the core object system used in GNOME, the main loop implementation, and a large set of utility functions for strings and common data structures.</description><homepage>https://wiki.gnome.org/Projects/GLib</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/readline4.xml"><name>GNU Readline Library</name><summary xml:lang="en">Get a line from a user with editing.</summary><description xml:lang="en">Readline offers editing capabilities while the user is entering the line. By default, the line editing commands are similar to those of emacs.</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.png" type="image/png"/><category>System</category><homepage>http://mingwrep.sourceforge.net/</homepage><entry-point binary-name="rl" command="run"/><entry-point binary-name="rlversion" command="rlversion">
    <needs-terminal/>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/gtk.xml"><name>GTK+ Runtime</name><summary>runtime components of GTK+</summary><description>This package contains the runtime components for GTK+.</description><homepage>http://www.gtk.org/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/gdbm.xml"><name>Gdbm</name><summary xml:lang="en">Gdbm: GNU database manager</summary><description xml:lang="en">The GNU `dbm' is a library of database functions that use extendible hashing and works similar to the standard UNIX `dbm' functions. These routines are provided to a programmer needing to create and manipulate a hashed database. </description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.png" type="image/png"/><category>System</category><homepage>http://gnuwin32.sourceforge.net/packages/gdbm.htm</homepage><entry-point binary-name="testgdbm" command="run">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">testgdbm</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">A simple test program</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="conv2gdbm" command="conv2gdbm">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">conv2gdbm</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">A dbm database conversion program</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="tdbm" command="tdbm">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">tdbm</name>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="testdbm" command="testdbm">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">testdbm</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">A simple test program</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="testndbm" command="testndbm">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">testndbm</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">A simple test program</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="tndbm" command="tndbm">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">tndbm</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">the gndbm test program</summary>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/libiconv.xml"><name>LibIconv</name><summary xml:lang="en">LibIconv: convert between character encodings</summary><description xml:lang="en">LibIconv converts from one character encoding to another through Unicode conversion (see Web page for full list of supported encodings). It has also limited support for transliteration, i.e. when a character cannot be represented in the target character set, it is approximated through one or several similar looking characters. It is useful if your application needs to support multiple character encodings, but that support lacks from your system. 
•Libiconv-1 is in Libiconv-1.7 
</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.png" type="image/png"/><category>Development</category><homepage>http://gnuwin32.sourceforge.net/packages/libiconv.htm</homepage><entry-point binary-name="iconv" command="run">
    <needs-terminal/>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/xslt.xml"><name>LibXslt</name><summary xml:lang="en">LibXslt: library and tools for applying XSLT to XML-documents</summary><description xml:lang="en">LibXslt is a library and tools for applying XSLT (Extensible Styleheets Transformations) to XML-documents. XML (Extensible Markup Language) is the universal format for data on the Web. XML is a metalanguage to design markup languages, i.e. text language where semantic and structure are added to the content using extra &quot;markup&quot; information enclosed between angle bracket. HTML is the most well-known markup language. </description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/xml2.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/xml2.png" type="image/png"/><category>Development</category><homepage>http://gnuwin32.sourceforge.net/packages/libxslt.htm</homepage><entry-point binary-name="xsltproc" command="run">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">xsltproc</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">xsltproc: command line xslt processor</summary>
    <description xml:lang="en">xsltproc  is  a  command  line  tool  for  applying XSLT
       stylesheets to XML documents. It is part of libxslt, the
       XSLT C library for GNOME. While it was developed as part
       of the GNOME project, it can  operate  independently  of
       the GNOME desktop.</description>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/msvc71.xml"><name>Microsoft Visual C++ 2003 Runtime</name><summary xml:lang="en">runtime components of Visual C++ Libraries</summary><description xml:lang="en">This package contains the runtime components required by applications compiled with Visual C++ 2003.</description><homepage>http://www.microsoft.com/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/msvc90.xml"><name>Microsoft Visual C++ 2008 Runtime</name><summary xml:lang="en">runtime components of Visual C++ Libraries</summary><description xml:lang="en">This package contains the runtime components required by applications compiled with Visual C++ 2008.</description><homepage>http://www.microsoft.com/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/msvc100.xml"><name>Microsoft Visual C++ 2010 Runtime</name><summary xml:lang="en">runtime components of Visual C++ Libraries</summary><description xml:lang="en">This package contains the runtime components required by applications compiled with Visual C++ 2010.</description><homepage>http://www.microsoft.com/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/netcdf.xml"><name>Network Common Data Form (NetCDF)</name><summary xml:lang="en">NetCDF is a set of software libraries and self-describing, machine-independent data formats that support the creation, access, and sharing of array-oriented scientific data.</summary><description xml:lang="en">NetCDF (network Common Data Form) is a set of interfaces for array-oriented data access and a freely distributed collection of data access libraries for C, Fortran, C++, Java, and other languages. The netCDF libraries support a machine-independent format for representing scientific data. Together, the interfaces, libraries, and format support the creation, access, and sharing of scientific data.</description><category>Science</category><homepage>https://www.unidata.ucar.edu/software/netcdf/</homepage><entry-point binary-name="ncdump" command="run">
    <needs-terminal/>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="ncgen" command="ncgen">
    <needs-terminal/>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="run_tests" command="test">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">run_tests</name>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/pcre.xml"><name>Pcre</name><summary xml:lang="en">Library of Perl-compatible regular expressions.</summary><description xml:lang="en">Library of Perl-compatible regular expressions.  I needed this to
  build Grep capable of &quot;grep -P&quot; mode.  (A newer version is available
  below, but this one is still required for the ported Grep.)

Version 8.36 of the library of Perl-compatible regular expressions.
  I needed this to build wget (below).

  The C++ bindings of this library is provided only as a static
  library, to avoid dependency on libstdc++ DLL.</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/pcre.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/pcre.png" type="image/png"/><category>Development</category><homepage>https://sourceforge.net/projects/ezwinports/files/</homepage><entry-point binary-name="pcregrep" command="run">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">pcregrep</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">a grep with Perl-compatible regular expressions.    </summary>
    <description xml:lang="en">pcregrep  searches  files for character patterns, in the
       same way as other grep commands do, but it uses the PCRE
       regular  expression library to support patterns that are
       compatible with the regular expressions of Perl  5.  See
       pcrepattern(3)  for  a  full  description  of syntax and
       semantics of the regular expressions that PCRE supports.

       Patterns,  whether  supplied on the command line or in a
       separate file, are given without delimiters.  For  exam-
       ple:

         pcregrep Thursday /etc/motd

       If  you  attempt to use delimiters (for example, by sur-
       rounding a pattern with slashes, as is  common  in  Perl
       scripts),  they  are interpreted as part of the pattern.
       Quotes can of course be used on the command line because
       they  are  interpreted by the shell, and indeed they are
       required if a pattern  contains  white  space  or  shell
       metacharacters.

       The  first  argument that follows any option settings is
       treated as the single pattern to be matched when neither
       -e  nor  -f is present.  Conversely, when one or both of
       these options are used to specify  patterns,  all  argu-
       ments are treated as path names. At least one of -e, -f,
       or an argument pattern must be provided.

       If no files are specified, pcregrep reads  the  standard
       input.  The  standard  input can also be referenced by a
       name consisting of a single hyphen.  For example:

         pcregrep some-pattern /file1 - /file3

       By default, each line that matches the pattern is copied
       to  the  standard  output, and if there is more than one
       file, the file name is output at the start of each line.
       However,  there are options that can change how pcregrep
       behaves. In particular, the -M option makes it  possible
       to  search  for patterns that span line boundaries. What
       defines a line boundary is controlled by the -N  (--new-
       line) option.

       Patterns   are  limited  to  8K  or  BUFSIZ  characters,
       whichever  is  the  greater.   BUFSIZ  is   defined   in
       &lt;stdio.h&gt;.

       If  the  LC_ALL or LC_CTYPE environment variable is set,
       pcregrep uses the value to set a locale when calling the
       PCRE  library.  The --locale option can be used to over-
       ride this.</description>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="pcretest" command="pcretest">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">Pcretest</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">a program for testing Perl-compatible regular expressions </summary>
    <description xml:lang="en">pcretest was written as a test program for the PCRE regular  expression library itself, but it can also be used
       for experimenting with regular expressions.  This  document  describes  the  features  of the test program; for
 details of the regular expressions themselves,  see  the
       pcrepattern  documentation.  For  details  of  the  PCRE
 library  function  calls  and  their  options,  see  the
       pcreapi documentation.
</description>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/readline5.xml"><name>Readline</name><summary xml:lang="en">Readline: edit command lines </summary><description xml:lang="en">The GNU Readline library provides a set of functions for use by applications that allow users to edit command lines as they are typed in. Both Emacs and vi editing modes are available. The Readline library includes additional functions to maintain a list of previously-entered command lines, to recall and perhaps reedit those lines, and perform csh-like history expansion on previous commands. 

The history facilites are also placed into a separate library, the History library, as part of the build process. The History library may be used without Readline in applications which desire its capabilities. 
</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.png" type="image/png"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><homepage>http://gnuwin32.sourceforge.net/packages/readline.htm</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/regex.xml"><name>Regex</name><summary xml:lang="en">Regex: searches for and matches text strings</summary><description xml:lang="en">A regular expression (or regexp, or pattern) is a text string that describes some set of strings. 

Using the Regex library, you can: 
•see if a string matches a specified pattern as a whole, and 
•search within a string for a substring matching a specified pattern. 

Regex provides three groups of functions with which you can operate on regular expressions. One group--the GNU group--is more powerful but not completely compatible with the other two, namely the POSIX and Berkeley UNIX groups; its interface was designed specifically for GNU. The other groups have the same interfaces as do the regular expression functions in POSIX and Berkeley UNIX. 
</description><homepage>http://www.gnu.org/directory/regex.html</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/xpm.xml"><name>Xpm</name><summary xml:lang="en">Xpm: library for X PixMap images</summary><category>Development</category><description xml:lang="en">XPixMap (XPM) consists of an ASCII image format and a C library. The format defines how to store color images (X Pixmap) in a portable and powerful way. The library provides a set of functions to store and retrieve images to and from XPM format data, being either files, buffers (files in memory), or data (included files). 

While XPM is not an X Consortium standard, it is already a de facto standard. It is used in many applications both commercial and non-commercial. Several vendors distribute the XPM library, as contributed software, on the platforms they sell. Moreover, the Common Desktop Environment specifies that icons must be stored either in XBM or XPM format. Finally, Motif 2.0 from OSF includes the XPM library, allowing XPM to be used in addition to XBM. 
</description><homepage>http://gnuwin32.sourceforge.net/packages/xpm.htm</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/curl3-gnutls.xml"><name>curl3-gnutls</name><summary>Multi-protocol file transfer library (GnuTLS)</summary><description>libcurl is designed to be a solid, usable, reliable and portable
multi-protocol file transfer library.

SSL support is provided by GnuTLS.

This is the shared version of libcurl.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/gcc-libs.xml"><name>gcc-libs</name><summary>GNU Compiler Collection (libraries) for MinGW-w64</summary><description/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.png" type="image/png"/><category>Development</category><homepage>https://gcc.gnu.org</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/gmp.xml"><name>gmp</name><summary xml:lang="en">A free library for arbitrary precision arithmetic (mingw-w64)</summary><description xml:lang="en"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/gmp.png" type="image/png"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/gmp.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><homepage>https://gmplib.org/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/cairo-dev.xml"><name>libcairo2-dev</name><summary>Development files for the Cairo 2D graphics library</summary><description>Cairo is a multi-platform library providing anti-aliased
vector-based rendering for multiple target backends.

This package contains the development libraries, header files needed by
programs that want to compile with Cairo.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/curl.xml"><name>libcurl</name><summary>libcurl is designed to be a solid, usable, reliable and portable multi-protocol file transfer library.</summary></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/expat1.xml"><name>libexpat1</name><summary>XML parsing C library - runtime library</summary><description>
This package contains the runtime, shared library of expat, the C library for
parsing XML.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/gc.xml"><name>libgc1c2</name><summary>conservative garbage collector for C and C++</summary><description>Boehm's GC is a garbage collecting storage allocator that is
intended to be used as a plug-in replacement for C's malloc.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/gcc1.xml"><name>libgcc1</name><summary>GCC support library</summary><description>Shared version of the support library, a library of internal subroutines
that GCC uses to overcome shortcomings of particular machines, or
special needs for some languages.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/glade2.xml"><name>libglade2</name><summary>library to load .glade files at runtime</summary><description>This library allows to load externally stored user interfaces into
programs. This allows alteration of the interface without recompilation
of the program.

The interfaces can also be edited with GLADE.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/gmp3c2.xml"><name>libgmp3c2</name><summary>multiprecision arithmetic library</summary><description>
GNU MP is a programmer's library for arbitrary precision arithmetic (ie, a
bignum package). It can operate on signed integer, rational, and floating point
numeric types.

It has a rich set of functions, and the functions have a regular interface.</description><homepage>http://gmplib.org/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/gnutls26.xml"><name>libgnutls26</name><summary>the GNU TLS library - runtime library</summary><description>gnutls is a portable library which implements the Transport Layer
Security (TLS) 1.0 and Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) 3.0 protocols.

Currently gnutls implements:
 - the TLS 1.0 and SSL 3.0 protocols, without any US-export
   controlled algorithms
 - X509 Public Key Infrastructure (with several limitations).
 - SRP for TLS authentication.
 - TLS Extension mechanism

This package contains the runtime libraries.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/gtkmm.xml"><name>libgtkmm</name><summary>C++ wrappers for GTK+ (shared libraries)</summary><description>Gtkmm is a C++ interface for the popular GUI library GTK+.
Gtkmm provides a convenient interface for C++ programmers to create
graphical user interfaces with GTK+'s flexible OO framework. Highlights
include type safe callbacks, widgets extensible using inheritance and
over 180 classes that can be freely combined to quickly create complex
user interfaces.

This package contains shared libraries.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/x-ice-dev.xml"><name>libice-dev</name><summary>X11 Inter-Client Exchange library (development headers)</summary><description>
This package provides the main interface to the X11 Inter-Client Exchange
library, which allows for communication of data between X clients.

This package contains the development headers for the library found in libice6.
Non-developers likely have little use for this package.

More information about X.Org can be found at: &lt;URL:http://xorg.freedesktop.org&gt;
&lt;URL:http://lists.freedesktop.org/mailman/listinfo/xorg&gt;</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/icu.xml"><name>libicu</name><summary>library that provides robust and full-featured Unicode and locale support</summary></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/krb53.xml"><name>libkrb53</name><summary>MIT Kerberos runtime libraries</summary><description>Kerberos is a system for authenticating users and services on a network.
Kerberos is a trusted third-party service. That means that there is a
third party (the Kerberos server) that is trusted by all the entities on
the network (users and services, usually called &quot;principals&quot;).

This is the MIT reference implementation of Kerberos V5.

This package contains the runtime libraries used by applications and
Kerberos clients.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/ldap-2.4-2.xml"><name>libldap-2.4-2</name><summary>OpenLDAP libraries</summary><description>These are the run-time libraries for the OpenLDAP (Lightweight Directory
Access Protocol) servers and clients.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/mpfr1ldbl.xml"><name>libmpfr1ldbl</name><summary>multiple precision floating-point computation</summary><description>
MPFR provides a library for multiple-precision floating-point computation with
correct rounding. The computation is both efficient and has a well-defined
semantics. It copies the good ideas from the ANSI/IEEE-754 standard for double-
precision floating-point arithmetic (53-bit mantissa).</description><homepage>http://www.mpfr.org/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/libpaper.xml"><name>libpaper</name><summary xml:lang="en">LibPaper: library and tools for handling papersize</summary><description xml:lang="en">The paper library and accompanying files are intended to provide a simple way for applications to take actions based on a system- or user-specified paper size. It lets program automatically recognize a lot of different papers with their properties (actually their size). It also includes a program for accessing paper information from shell scripts. 

This release is quite minimal, its purpose being to provide really basic functions (obtaining the system paper name and getting the height and width of a given kond of paper) that applications can immediately integrate. 
</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/libpaper.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/libpaper.png" type="image/png"/><category>Development</category><homepage>http://gnuwin32.sourceforge.net/packages/libpaper.htm</homepage><entry-point binary-name="paperconf" command="run">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">Paperconf</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">Paperconf: print paper configuration informations</summary>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/png12-0.xml"><name>libpng12-0</name><summary>PNG library - runtime</summary><description>libpng is a library implementing an interface for reading and writing
PNG (Portable Network Graphics) format files.

This package contains the runtime library files needed to run software
using libpng.</description><homepage>http://libpng.org/pub/png/libpng.html</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/png16-0.xml"><name>libpng16-0</name><summary>A collection of routines used to create PNG format graphics</summary><description>libpng is a library implementing an interface for reading and writing
PNG (Portable Network Graphics) format files.

This package contains the runtime library files needed to run software
using libpng.</description><category>Graphics</category><homepage>http://www.libpng.org/pub/png/libpng.html</homepage><entry-point binary-name="pngfix" command="run">
  <needs-terminal/>
    <name>pngfix</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">Tests, optimizes and optionally fixes the zlib header in PNG files.</summary>
    </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="png-fix-itxt" command="png-fix-itxt">
  <needs-terminal/>
        <name>png-fix-itxt</name>
    	<summary xml:lang="en">Fixes a PNG file written with libpng-1.6.0 or 1.6.1 that has one or more uncompressed iTXt chunks.</summary>
    </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/popt.xml"><name>libpopt0</name><summary>lib for parsing cmdline parameters</summary><description>Popt was heavily influenced by the getopt() and getopt_long() functions,
but it allows more powerful argument expansion. It can parse arbitrary
argv[] style arrays and automatically set variables based on command
line arguments. It also allows command line arguments to be aliased via
configuration files and includes utility functions for parsing arbitrary
strings into argv[] arrays using shell-like rules.

This package contains the runtime library and locale data.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/readline6.xml"><name>libreadline6</name><summary>GNU readline and history libraries, run-time libraries</summary><description>The GNU readline library aids in the consistency of user interface
across discrete programs that need to provide a command line
interface.

The GNU history library provides a consistent user interface for
recalling lines of previously typed input.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/x-sm-dev.xml"><name>libsm-dev</name><summary>X11 Session Management library (development headers)</summary><description>
This package provides the main interface to the X11 Session Management library,
which allows for applications to both manage sessions, and make use of session
managers to save and restore their state for later use.

This package contains the development headers for the library found in libsm6.
Non-developers likely have little use for this package.

More information about X.Org can be found at: &lt;URL:http://www.X.org&gt;
&lt;URL:http://xorg.freedesktop.org&gt;
&lt;URL:http://lists.freedesktop.org/mailman/listinfo/xorg&gt;

This module can be found at git://anongit.freedesktop.org/git/xorg/lib/libSM</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/stdc++6.xml"><name>libstdc++6</name><summary>The GNU Standard C++ Library v3</summary><description>This package contains an additional runtime library for C++ programs
built with the GNU compiler.

libstdc++-v3 is a complete rewrite from the previous libstdc++-v2, which
was included up to g++-2.95. The first version of libstdc++-v3 appeared
in g++-3.0.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/tasn1-3.xml"><name>libtasn1-3</name><summary>Manage ASN.1 structures (runtime)</summary><description>Manage ASN1 (Abstract Syntax Notation One) structures.
The main features of this library are:
  * on-line ASN1 structure management that doesn't require any C code
    file generation.
  * off-line ASN1 structure management with C code file generation
    containing an array.
  * DER (Distinguish Encoding Rules) encoding
  * no limits for INTEGER and ENUMERATED values

This package contains runtime libraries.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/tinfo5.xml"><name>libtinfo5</name><summary>legacy version of the shared low-level terminfo library</summary></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/unwind.xml"><name>libunwind</name><summary>library to determine the call-chain of a program</summary></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/libwinpthread.xml"><name>libwinpthread-git</name><summary>MinGW-w64 winpthreads library</summary><description/><homepage>https://mingw-w64.sourceforge.io/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/xml2.xml"><name>libxml2</name><summary>GNOME XML library</summary><description>XML is a metalanguage to let you design your own markup language.
A regular markup language defines a way to describe information in
a certain class of documents (eg HTML). XML lets you define your
own customized markup languages for many classes of document. It
can do this because it's written in SGML, the international standard
metalanguage for markup languages.

This package provides a library providing an extensive API to handle
such XML data files.</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/xml2.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/xml2.png" type="image/png"/><category>Development</category><homepage>http://xmlsoft.org/</homepage><entry-point binary-name="xmllint" command="xmllint">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">xmllint</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">command line XML tool</summary>
    <description xml:lang="en">The xmllint program parses one or more XML files, speci-
       fied  on  the command line as xmlfile. It prints various
       types of output, depending upon the options selected. It
       is  useful  for detecting errors both in XML code and in
       the XML parser itself.</description>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="xmlcatalog" command="xmlcatalog">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">xmlcatalog</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">Command line tool to parse and manipulate XML or SGML catalog files.</summary>
    <description xml:lang="en">xmlcatalog is a command line application allowing  users
       to  monitor  and manipulate XML and SGML catalogs. It is
       included in libxml2.
       Its functions can be invoked from a single command  from
       the  command  line, or it can perform multiple functions
       in interactive mode. It can operate on both XML and SGML
       files.</description>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/gnumpc.xml"><name>mpc</name><summary>Multiple precision complex arithmetic library (mingw-w64)</summary><description/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.png" type="image/png"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><homepage>http://www.multiprecision.org</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/mpfr4.xml"><name>mpfr</name><summary xml:lang="en">Multiple-precision floating-point library (mingw-w64)</summary><description/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/mpfr.png" type="image/png"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/lib/mpfr.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/ncurses.xml"><name>ncurses</name><summary xml:lang="en">terminal-independent  text-based user interface library</summary><description xml:lang="en">The ncurses (new curses) library is a free software emulation of curses in System V Release 4.0 (SVr4), and more. It uses terminfo format, supports pads and color and multiple highlights and forms characters and function-key mapping, and has all the other SVr4-curses enhancements over BSD curses. SVr4 curses became the basis of X/Open Curses.</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps/master/utils/gnu.png" type="image/png"/><category>Development</category><homepage>https://sourceforge.net/projects/ezwinports/files/</homepage><entry-point binary-name="captoinfo" command="captoinfo">
    <name xml:lang="en">captoinfo</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en"> a termcap conversion tool</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="clear" command="clear">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">clear</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">utility for clearing the screen</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="infocmp" command="infocmp">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">infocmp</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">the terminfo decompiler</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="infotocap" command="infotocap">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">infotocap</name>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="reset" command="reset">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">reset</name>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="tabs" command="tabs">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">tabs</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">set tabs on a terminal</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="tic" command="tic">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">tic</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">the terminfo compiler</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="toe" command="toe">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">toe</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">list (table of) terminfo entries</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="tput" command="tput">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">tput</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">utility for retrieving terminal capabilities in shell scripts</summary>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="tset" command="tset">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">tset</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">to initialize the terminal</summary>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/pthreads-win32.xml"><name>pthreads-win32</name><summary xml:lang="en">Open Source POSIX Threads for Win32</summary><description xml:lang="en">GNUC/not dependent on exceptions version
The POSIX 1003.1-2001 standard defines an application programming interface (API) for writing multithreaded applications. This interface is known more commonly as pthreads. A good number of modern operating systems include a threading library of some kind: Solaris (UI) threads, Win32 threads, DCE threads, DECthreads, or any of the draft revisions of the pthreads standard. The trend is that most of these systems are slowly adopting the pthreads standard API, with application developers following suit to reduce porting woes.  
Win32 does not, and is unlikely to ever, support pthreads natively. This project seeks to provide a freely available and high-quality solution to this problem. 
</description><category>Development</category><homepage>http://www.sourceware.org/pthreads-win32</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/x11proto-core-dev.xml"><name>x11proto-core-dev</name><summary>X11 core wire protocol and auxiliary headers</summary><description>
This package provides development headers describing the wire protocol for the
core X11 protocol, and also provides a number of utility headers, used to
abstract OS-specific functions.

This package deprecates 'x-dev', a package from the monolithic builds of XFree86
and X.Org.

More information about X.Org can be found at: &lt;URL:http://www.X.org&gt;
&lt;URL:http://xorg.freedesktop.org&gt;
&lt;URL:http://lists.freedesktop.org/mailman/listinfo/xorg&gt;

This package is built from the X.org xproto proto module.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/zlib.xml"><name>zlib</name><summary xml:lang="en">Compression library implementing the deflate compression method found in gzip and PKZIP</summary><description xml:lang="en">zlib is designed to be a free, general-purpose, legally unencumbered -- that is, not covered by any patents -- lossless data-compression library for use on virtually any computer hardware and operating system. The zlib data format is itself portable across platforms. Unlike the LZW compression method used in Unix compress(1) and in the GIF image format, the compression method currently used in zlib essentially never expands the data. (LZW can double or triple the file size in extreme cases.) zlib's memory footprint is also independent of the input data and can be reduced, if necessary, at some cost in compression. </description><icon href="http://www.zlib.net/favicon.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><icon href="http://www.zlib.net/images/zlib3d-b1.png" type="image/png"/><homepage>http://www.zlib.net/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/lib/zlib1g.xml"><name>zlib1g</name><summary>compression library - runtime</summary><description>zlib is a library implementing the deflate compression method found
in gzip and PKZIP. This package includes the shared library.</description></interface></c:catalog>
<!-- Base64 Signature
iQEzBAABCgAdFiEEiMih83WShpHXNlwCWao5J8JOTh4FAl8aq3kACgkQWao5J8JOTh6kkwf/cHQP
bkPCgh7eWF3p8LyBoLD3F+yPvM/hZL1pWEvULOUwlaGgjot2cjNUhWNDiK+DJgRoNWMRN9mQ66kp
Z3HXHQfHUCOmNai1vXSceDNqfzg58ycZUIH9dPr+wFKAYmPj88BwzbfYtr6oNbiRsyndd4lgc7VM
/zRc+QJU8Y3T9CXFBp7NFAqZ4LkEor6F5TEbzuGHpK5rEqAIcK/oySca4weQuLEIC1L5vZ1VJynp
2fr1cLWlwctIkJ+LYpBDr07hYP5iVVndfCcL0Ro7hylGUkzUBJrDsOBeoYeshRvC2umCO1z2BGvk
YygjppvzP9koSJKEyK3hVfobZYca2Hm31w==

-->
