<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='interface.xsl'?>
<interface uri="http://repo.roscidus.com/lib/pcre" xmlns="http://zero-install.sourceforge.net/2004/injector/interface" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://zero-install.sourceforge.net/2004/injector/interface http://0install.de/schema/injector/interface/interface.xsd http://0install.de/schema/desktop-integration/capabilities http://0install.de/schema/desktop-integration/capabilities/capabilities.xsd">
  <name>Pcre</name>
  <summary xml:lang="en">Library of Perl-compatible regular expressions.</summary>
  <description xml:lang="en">Library of Perl-compatible regular expressions.  I needed this to
  build Grep capable of &quot;grep -P&quot; mode.  (A newer version is available
  below, but this one is still required for the ported Grep.)

Version 8.36 of the library of Perl-compatible regular expressions.
  I needed this to build wget (below).

  The C++ bindings of this library is provided only as a static
  library, to avoid dependency on libstdc++ DLL.</description>
  <icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/repo.roscidus.com/master/lib/pcre.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/>
  <icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/repo.roscidus.com/master/lib/pcre.png" type="image/png"/>
  <category>Development</category>
  <homepage>https://sourceforge.net/projects/ezwinports/files/</homepage>
  <needs-terminal/>
  <group arch="Windows-i486" >
    <command name="run" path="bin/pcregrep.exe"/>
    <command name="pcretest" path="bin/pcretest.exe"/>
    <implementation license="BSD License (revised)" id="sha1new=492099b5e85f1418a80d446def4f0469b3e28ad2" released="2007-03-23" version="7.0">
      <manifest-digest sha256new="23EYS5LDQ74KOXLXLSRANWAHRAM5YJ2NCO53Q3RSWKYGUXAN6UIA"/>
      <archive href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/gnuwin32/files/pcre/7.0/pcre-7.0-bin.zip" size="302480" type="application/zip"/>
      <archive href="https://github.com/kkeybbs/gnuwin32/blob/master/gnuwin32/pcre-bin.zip" size="302480" type="application/zip"/>
    </implementation>
    <implementation license="BSD License (revised), GPL v2 (GNU General Public License), BZIP2, MIT/X Consortium License, zlib/libpng license" id="sha1new=8f4cfac1071b28cf5c7900e7a3ee8d2b7599af2e" released="2012-02-03" version="8.21">
      <manifest-digest sha256new="4F7ZCHGTOGHRBCSKR67ZJ7TMRCXN5YTAFQHATF3JWQYBPIWWCE7A"/>
      <archive href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/ezwinports/files/pcre-8.21-w32-bin.zip" size="1112632" type="application/zip"/>
    </implementation>
    <implementation id="sha1new=3779bb85a4712ea55497aa81e456038544f46ad0" released="2014-12-22" version="8.36">
      <manifest-digest sha256new="CQLN7EW4CRRKGQWN3U5O2JYAW5JPOLN2DVHHX2OPZJLWKNF457AQ"/>
      <archive href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/ezwinports/files/pcre-8.36-w32-bin.zip" size="2101201" type="application/zip"/>
    </implementation>
  </group>
  <entry-point binary-name="pcregrep" command="run">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">pcregrep</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">a grep with Perl-compatible regular expressions.    </summary>
    <description xml:lang="en">pcregrep  searches  files for character patterns, in the
       same way as other grep commands do, but it uses the PCRE
       regular  expression library to support patterns that are
       compatible with the regular expressions of Perl  5.  See
       pcrepattern(3)  for  a  full  description  of syntax and
       semantics of the regular expressions that PCRE supports.

       Patterns,  whether  supplied on the command line or in a
       separate file, are given without delimiters.  For  exam-
       ple:

         pcregrep Thursday /etc/motd

       If  you  attempt to use delimiters (for example, by sur-
       rounding a pattern with slashes, as is  common  in  Perl
       scripts),  they  are interpreted as part of the pattern.
       Quotes can of course be used on the command line because
       they  are  interpreted by the shell, and indeed they are
       required if a pattern  contains  white  space  or  shell
       metacharacters.

       The  first  argument that follows any option settings is
       treated as the single pattern to be matched when neither
       -e  nor  -f is present.  Conversely, when one or both of
       these options are used to specify  patterns,  all  argu-
       ments are treated as path names. At least one of -e, -f,
       or an argument pattern must be provided.

       If no files are specified, pcregrep reads  the  standard
       input.  The  standard  input can also be referenced by a
       name consisting of a single hyphen.  For example:

         pcregrep some-pattern /file1 - /file3

       By default, each line that matches the pattern is copied
       to  the  standard  output, and if there is more than one
       file, the file name is output at the start of each line.
       However,  there are options that can change how pcregrep
       behaves. In particular, the -M option makes it  possible
       to  search  for patterns that span line boundaries. What
       defines a line boundary is controlled by the -N  (--new-
       line) option.

       Patterns   are  limited  to  8K  or  BUFSIZ  characters,
       whichever  is  the  greater.   BUFSIZ  is   defined   in
       &lt;stdio.h&gt;.

       If  the  LC_ALL or LC_CTYPE environment variable is set,
       pcregrep uses the value to set a locale when calling the
       PCRE  library.  The --locale option can be used to over-
       ride this.</description>
  </entry-point>
  <entry-point binary-name="pcretest" command="pcretest">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">Pcretest</name>
    <summary xml:lang="en">a program for testing Perl-compatible regular expressions </summary>
    <description xml:lang="en">pcretest was written as a test program for the PCRE regular  expression library itself, but it can also be used
       for experimenting with regular expressions.  This  document  describes  the  features  of the test program; for
 details of the regular expressions themselves,  see  the
       pcrepattern  documentation.  For  details  of  the  PCRE
 library  function  calls  and  their  options,  see  the
       pcreapi documentation.
</description>
  </entry-point>
</interface>
