<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../resources/catalog.xsl'?>
<c:catalog xmlns="http://zero-install.sourceforge.net/2004/injector/interface" xmlns:c="http://0install.de/schema/injector/catalog"><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/python/docutils.xml"><name>Docutils</name><summary>processes plaintext into HTML, XML, LaTeX, etc</summary><description>
Docutils is an open-source text processing system for processing plaintext
documentation into useful formats, such as HTML, LaTeX, man-pages, open-document
or XML. It includes reStructuredText, the easy to read, easy to use, what-you-
see-is-what-you-get plaintext markup language.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/python/pycairo.xml"><name>PyCairo</name><summary>Python bindings for the Cairo graphics library</summary><description>Pycairo is a set of Python bindings for the cairo graphics library.</description><homepage>http://cairographics.org/pycairo/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/python/pygobject.xml"><name>PyGObject</name><summary>Python bindings for the GObject library</summary><description>
GObject is an abstraction layer that allows programming with an object
paradigm that is compatible with many languages. It is a part of Glib,
the core library used to build GTK+ and GNOME.
  </description><homepage>https://pygobject.readthedocs.io/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/python/pygtk.xml"><name>PyGTK</name><summary>Python bindings for GTK+</summary><description>PyGTK lets you to easily create programs with a graphical user interface using the Python programming language. The underlying GTK+ library provides all kind of visual elements and utilities for it and, if needed, you can develop full featured applications for the GNOME Desktop.</description><homepage>https://pygobject.readthedocs.io/</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/python/pywin32.xml"><name>PyWin32</name><summary>Python for Windows Extensions</summary><description>The Python for Windows Extensions provide bindings for the Win32 API.</description><homepage>https://github.com/mhammond/pywin32</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/python/pyyaml.xml"><name>PyYAML</name><summary>YAML parser and emitter for Python</summary><description>The next generation YAML parser and emitter for Python.</description><homepage>https://github.com/yaml/pyyaml</homepage></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/python/python.xml"><name>Python</name><summary>interactive high-level object-oriented language</summary><description>
Python is an interpreted, interactive, object-oriented programming language. It
combines remarkable power with very clear syntax, and isn't difficult to learn.
It has modules, classes, exceptions, very high level data types, and dynamic
typing. There are interfaces to many system calls and libraries, as well as to
various windowing systems (Tk, Mac, MFC, GTK+, Qt, wxWindows). New built-in
modules are easily written in C or C++. Python is also usable as an extension
language for applications that need a programmable interface.</description><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps.0install.net/master/python/python.png" type="image/png"/><icon href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/0install/apps.0install.net/master/python/python.ico" type="image/vnd.microsoft.icon"/><entry-point binary-name="python" command="run">
    <needs-terminal/>
    <name xml:lang="en">Python command-line interpreter</name>
    <name xml:lang="de">Python Befehlszeileninterpreter</name>
  </entry-point><entry-point binary-name="pythonw" command="run-gui">
    <name xml:lang="en">Python GUI interpreter</name>
    <name xml:lang="de">Python Grafischer Interpreter</name>
  </entry-point></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/python/sphinx.xml"><name>Sphinx</name><summary>tool for producing documentation for Python projects</summary><description>
Sphinx is a tool that makes it easy to create intelligent and beautiful
documentation. It was originally created for the new Python documentation, and
it has excellent facilities for the documentation of Python projects, but C/C++
is already supported as well, and it is planned to add special support for other
languages as well.</description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/python/whoosh.xml"><name>Whoosh</name><summary>fast, pure-Python full text indexing, search, and spell checking library</summary><homepage>http://bitbucket.org/mchaput/whoosh</homepage><description>
    Whoosh is a fast, featureful full-text indexing and searching library
    implemented in pure Python. Programmers can use it to easily add search
    functionality to their applications and websites. Every part of how Whoosh
    works can be extended or replaced to meet your needs exactly.

    Some of Whoosh's features include:

    * Pythonic API.
    * Pure-Python. No compilation or binary packages needed, no mysterious crashes.
    * Fielded indexing and search.
    * Fast indexing and retrieval -- faster than any other pure-Python, scoring,
    full-text search solution I know of.
    * Pluggable scoring algorithm (including BM25F), text analysis, storage,
    posting format, etc.
    * Powerful query language.
    * Pure Python spell-checker (as far as I know, the only one). 

    Whoosh might be useful in the following circumstances:

    * Anywhere a pure-Python solution is desirable to avoid having to build/compile
    native libraries (or force users to build/compile them).
    * As a research platform (at least for programmers that find Python easier to
    read and work with than Java ;)
    * When an easy-to-use Pythonic interface is more important to you than raw
    speed. 

    Whoosh was created and is maintained by Matt Chaput. It was originally created
    for use in the online help system of Side Effects Software's 3D animation
    software Houdini. Side Effects Software Inc. graciously agreed to open-source
    the code.

    This software is licensed under the terms of the simplified BSD (A.K.A. &quot;two
    clause&quot; or &quot;FreeBSD&quot;) license. See LICENSE.txt for information.
  </description></interface><interface uri="https://apps.0install.net/python/dbus-python.xml"><name>dbus-python</name><summary>dbus-python</summary><description/></interface></c:catalog>
<!-- Base64 Signature
iQEzBAABCgAdFiEEiMih83WShpHXNlwCWao5J8JOTh4FAl4d3X4ACgkQWao5J8JOTh5dHAf/YCrS
N1EoVZSphaFw4IT7k+8zCwEArDQl7B1Cx1QfS8VnA3elR5azqRDU7ciQSqX8naM31y93h35XVjjw
1D9jSXRbM2HWpaYBx9giAVw0VBoJZ5GT/pdUDGZ0dA+opPs9+Czk2tanu/d0qFby0dPyVhjTJPxr
4Povq+PE4awJzYHygM6HNO7olujRuQTo7xJ6QWavUcxgDaeItyS7yTPXVX2F2D6iJkCm06pNOv+h
H2VAAddsJbJOzoXRhFAyIP+bWT6Vhd6/XuAhPbj3OT0A/ObJzDxgShRwlwGG19kEQRwUEg+7+mbX
hH3ivXRA5syZZQQlX4SMQBWABbJBpK8o1g==

-->
