<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='interface.xsl'?>
<interface uri="http://repo.roscidus.com/python/whoosh" xmlns="http://zero-install.sourceforge.net/2004/injector/interface" xmlns:compile="http://zero-install.sourceforge.net/2006/namespaces/0compile" xmlns:gfxmonk="http://gfxmonk.net/dist/0install">
  <name>python-whoosh</name>
  <summary>fast, pure-Python full text indexing, search, and spell checking library</summary>
  <gfxmonk:upstream id="Whoosh" type="pypi"/>
  <gfxmonk:publish>third-party</gfxmonk:publish>
  <homepage>http://bitbucket.org/mchaput/whoosh</homepage>
  <description>
    Whoosh is a fast, featureful full-text indexing and searching library
    implemented in pure Python. Programmers can use it to easily add search
    functionality to their applications and websites. Every part of how Whoosh
    works can be extended or replaced to meet your needs exactly.

    Some of Whoosh's features include:

    * Pythonic API.
    * Pure-Python. No compilation or binary packages needed, no mysterious crashes.
    * Fielded indexing and search.
    * Fast indexing and retrieval -- faster than any other pure-Python, scoring,
    full-text search solution I know of.
    * Pluggable scoring algorithm (including BM25F), text analysis, storage,
    posting format, etc.
    * Powerful query language.
    * Pure Python spell-checker (as far as I know, the only one). 

    Whoosh might be useful in the following circumstances:

    * Anywhere a pure-Python solution is desirable to avoid having to build/compile
    native libraries (or force users to build/compile them).
    * As a research platform (at least for programmers that find Python easier to
    read and work with than Java ;)
    * When an easy-to-use Pythonic interface is more important to you than raw
    speed. 

    Whoosh was created and is maintained by Matt Chaput. It was originally created
    for use in the online help system of Side Effects Software's 3D animation
    software Houdini. Side Effects Software Inc. graciously agreed to open-source
    the code.

    This software is licensed under the terms of the simplified BSD (A.K.A. &quot;two
    clause&quot; or &quot;FreeBSD&quot;) license. See LICENSE.txt for information.
  </description>
  <group>
    <environment insert="src" name="PYTHONPATH"/>
    <implementation id="sha1new=6069e9f59d6fab618f32e7294490021cec0caaeb" released="2012-06-16" version="2.4.1">
      <archive extract="Whoosh-2.4.1" href="https://pypi.python.org/packages/source/W/Whoosh/Whoosh-2.4.1.tar.gz" size="938446"/>
      <manifest-digest sha256="741baed545d22b9448d990c44aaf7e2c695b88198982ae3354965840acb5428f"/>
    </implementation>
  </group>
</interface>
